<chapter id="seahaven">
<docinfo>
  <copyright>
   <year>2001</year>
   <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
  </copyright>
  <author>
   <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
   <surname>Yuen</surname>
  </author>
  <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
</docinfo>

<title>Seahaven</title>
  <para>written by Rosanna Yuen</para>
  <bridgehead>Setup</bridgehead>

  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Type of Deck</entry>
	  <entry>Standard Deck</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Foundations</entry>
	  <entry>Four piles -- two top left, two top right.  Built from
	  Ace to King in suit.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Reserves</entry>
	  <entry>Four piles at top in the center.  Each reserve can only
	  hold one card.  Two of the reserves are each dealt one card to
	  start.</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Tableau</entry>
	  <entry>Ten piles underneath the Foundation and Reserves.  The
	  other fifty cards are dealt face up here with five in each
	  slot.</entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

  <bridgehead>Goal</bridgehead>
  <para>
    Move all cards to the Foundation piles.
  </para>
  <bridgehead>Rules</bridgehead>
  <para>
    The Tableau is built down by suit.  Only the top card or build of
    cards can be moved.  A build of cards can only be moved if the
    number of cards in the build is equal or less than one more than the
    number of Reserve slots free.  Empty spaces in the Tableau can only
    be filled with a King or a build starting with a King.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up by suit from Ace to King.  Although cards
    in the Foundations are technically still in play, there really is no
    need as playing these cards are not in any way helpful.
  </para>
  <para>
    Any top card in the Tableau can be placed in an empty Reserve slot.
    These cards are available for play back into the Tableau or on to a
    Foundation pile.
  </para>
  <bridgehead>Options</bridgehead>
  <para>None</para>
  <bridgehead>Scoring</bridgehead>
  <para>
    Each card placed on to the Foundation piles scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  52
  </para>
  <bridgehead>Strategy</bridgehead>
  <para>
    Move any card you can on to the Foundations as soon as possible.
    Leaving them around can only hinder your movement.
  </para>
</chapter>
<!-- Keep this comment at the end of the file
Local variables:
sgml-default-dtd-file: "/usr/lib/sgml/cdtd/docbook.ced"
End:
-->
