<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
                   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<sect1 id="Australian_Patience"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>2022</year>
      <holder>Gwyneth Morgan</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Gwyneth</firstname>
      <surname>Morgan</surname>
    </author>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Australian Patience</title>

  <sect2>
    <title>Setup</title>

    <informaltable>
      <tgroup cols="2"><tbody>
        <row>
          <entry>Type of Deck</entry>
          <entry>Standard Deck</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Stock</entry>
          <entry>
            Single pile, top-left.  The rest of the deck
            is placed here after dealing on to the Tableau.  Cards are turned
            over one at a time to Waste.
          </entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Waste</entry>
          <entry>
            Single pile to the right of the Stock.  To be taken from Stock.
            Top card available for play.
          </entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Foundation</entry>
          <entry>
            Four piles, top-right, built up in suit from Ace to King.
          </entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>Tableau</entry>
          <entry>
            Seven piles.  Four cards are dealt to each pile when the game
            starts.  Build down in suit.  Empty spaces can be filled with a
            King.  Any number of cards may be moved at once so long as the
            bottom card is the same suit and one less in value than the top of
            the target pile.
          </entry>
        </row>
      </tbody></tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Goal</title>

    <para>
      Move all cards to the Foundation piles.
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Rules</title>

    <para>
      Cards in the Tableau are built down by suit.  Any number of cards may be
      moved at once so long as the bottom card is the same suit and one less in
      value than the top of the target pile.  This means you may move a pile of
      cards that do not build down in suit, so long as the two contacting cards
      do.
    </para>
    <para>
      Empty spaces can be filled with a King.
    </para>
    <para>
      Foundations are built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in the
      Foundations are no longer in play.  Double clicking on a card will move
      it to the appropriate Foundation pile if such a move is
      possible.
    </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2>
    <title>Scoring</title>

    <para>
      Each card in the Foundation piles scores one point.
    </para>
    <para>
      Maximum possible score: 52
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
