<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE refentry PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
                   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<sect1 id="Thumb_And_Pouch"><!--<sect1info>
    <copyright>
      <year>1999</year>
      <holder>Rosanna Yuen</holder>
    </copyright>
    <author>
      <firstname>Rosanna</firstname>
      <surname>Yuen</surname>
    </author>
    <address><email>zana@webwynk.net</email></address>
  </sect1info>-->

  <title>Thumb and Pouch</title>

  <para>Written by Rosanna Yuen</para>

          <sect2><title>Setup</title>


  <informaltable>
    <tgroup cols="2">
      <tbody>
	<row>
	  <entry>Type of Deck</entry>
	  <entry>Standard Deck</entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Stock</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Top left pile.  The rest of the deck is placed here after
	    dealing on to the Tableau.  Cards are turned over one at a
	    time to Waste.  Two redeals.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Waste</entry>
	  <entry>
	    To be taken from Stock.  Top card available for
	    play.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Foundation</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Four piles top right.  To be built up in suit from Ace to
	    King.  Topmost card in each Foundation can be played back on
	    to the Tableau.
	  </entry>
	</row>
	<row>
	  <entry>Tableau</entry>
	  <entry>
	    Seven piles.  Deal card face up in first pile.  Place one
	    card face down on all other piles.  Place one card face up
	    on next pile followed by one card face down on all covered
	    piles.  Repeat until there are seven cards in last pile.
	    Tableau can be built down in any suit but own.  Groups of
	    cards can be moved.  Empty piles can be filled by any legal
	    sequence of cards.
	  </entry>
	</row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </informaltable>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Goal</title>

  <para>
    Move all cards to the Foundation piles.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Rules</title>

  <para>
    Cards in the Tableau are built down by any suit but own.  Groups of
    cards can be moved.  An empty pile in the Tableau can be filled with
    any legal sequence of cards.
  </para>
  <para>
    Cards are flipped from the stock to the Waste individually.  Top
    card in Waste is in play.  When Stock is empty, move all cards in
    Waste back to the Stock, maintaining order. You can go through the
    deck three times.
  </para>
  <para>
    Foundations are built up in suit from Ace to King.  Cards in
    Foundations are still in play.  Double clicking on a card will move
    it to the appropriate Foundation pile if such a move is possible.
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Scoring</title>

  <para>
    Each card in the Foundation piles scores one point.
  </para>
  <para>
    Maximum possible score:  52
  </para>

          </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Strategy</title>

  <para>
    Brute force may not always work, but in this case it probably will.
  </para>
        </sect2>
</sect1>
